Edekobi Philip

Software Engineer

• 4, Betty Pride Way, Ajao Estate, Lagos, Nigeria # 30/01/2004 in Philip Edekobi

Luxury.dev luxury.dev

Summary

My most prominent quality as an engineer is that I love to build stuff. I naturally love to figure out how things work and I take interest in a lot of engineering aspects. Most of my experience is concentrated in backend and systems related activities, including highly scalable and maintainable APIs, system design and database design.

I am currently completing a degree in Software Engineering from Babcock University.

Skills

Javascript & Typescript, NodeJs, Go, Linux, Aws, React/Next.js, SQL and NoSQL Databases

Professional Experience

Internship, *Ritemate Technologies* □

01/2023 - 06/2023 | Lagos, Nigeria

I worked as a full stack developer, building and shipping multiple products for in-house use and also external clients. These products included: CLI's, Web Applications and APIs. In this role, I had the opportunity of extending my skill set by picking up new programming languages and frameworks which include: PHP, Laravel and Codelgniter. I was also prodded to wear multiple hats for the organization by participating in QA and

Software Engineer, Foodsub □

Requirements engineering.

11/2021 - 09/2022 | Lagos, Nigeria

As, the only backend engineer on the project at the initial stages, I built all the initial API endpoints e.g the user registration and login endpoints and the food storage and delivery endpoints.

I also worked for a while with the frontend team on the landing page.

The highlight of being in this role was optimizing the email delivery process. At a certain scale, our servers started choking due to the amount of emails that needed to be sent in the same thread as the application so I designed a system based on message queues distributed over different threads to deliver the emails.

Education

B.Sc Software Engineering, Babcock University □

01/2021 - 06/2024

Illisan-Remo, Nigeria

A rigorous scholarly period filled with mathematical and advanced computer science and software engineering course work.

Student Communities

Google Developer Student Club Babcock,

08/2022 - 06/2024

Dev team member ☑

Illisan-Remo, Ogun State, Nigeria

The Google Developer Student Club(GDSC) is an organization created by Google for students to have a united community to learn about programming together.

As a member, my role included helping in implementing software that would facilitate the operations of the organization on campus, teaching and guiding junior students with less experience than me and taking parts in efforts to increase the interest of the remainder of the student populace in software.

Enactus Babcock, Developer team member ☑

01/2022 - 06/2024

Illisan-Remo, Ogun State, Nigeria

Enactus is an experiential learning platform that gives students a platform to assess and provide solutions to the needs of their immediate community.

As a dev team member, I had some responsibilities on working on software aspects of our solutions to problems. An example is a web app for farmers to advertise their products to a wider audience.